Guide to the Alexander Haight family collection, 1764-1977
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Alexander Haight family collection
1764-1977
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Alexander Haight
C0159
13 linear feet (19 boxes and 12 unboxed objects)
This collection contains materials of the Haight family, who have lived in Northern Virginia since the 1840s, and who owned Sully Plantation during the Civil War. Materials include correspondence, household financial records, photographs, Civil War documents, and artifacts. The artifacts in the collection consist of American Indian arrowheads and Civil War relics. Most of the materials date from the mid to late 19th century and the early 20th century, but the collection also includes a ledger dating from before the American Revolution and a few items dating from after the First World War.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Alexander Levi Haight in 1978.
Biographical Information
Alexander Haight (1822-1880), son of Amy C. Haight (1787-1863) and Jacob Haight (1782-1862), lived at Sully Plantation from 1842-1874. Quaker farmers from Dutchess County, New York, the Haights moved to Sully at the urging of Jacob, who delighted in the milder climate and extensive farm land, which they enhanced with lime and guano fertilizers. In 1845, Alexander married Phebe Sweet (1824-1898), and in 1851 they finished building their new home, "Little Sully," on Haight property just south of the main Sully house.
The effects of the Civil War on daily life in Northern Virginia are evident from the personal letters and military documents that have been preserved. Phebe and her sister-in-law, Maria Haight Barlow, were left to defend their homes when Jacob and Alexander were forced to flee to Alexandria and Washington to avoid incoming Confederate troops who suspected the Haights of being Union sympathizers. The Haights did, in fact, support the Union, and toward the end of the war Alexander Haight joined the Union Army.
Many of the documents in this collection indicate something of the precarious position in which the Haights were caught during the Civil War. These include receipts for provisions supplied by the Haight farm to both the Union and Confederate armies; a letter from Union Major General Julius Stahel attesting to the good standing of Alexander Haight and ordering the protection of his property by Union troops; and a court memorandum offering the transport of Alexander Haight to and from his trial over the confiscation of property during the war.
Alexander Levi Haight (1891-1981), the eponymous donor of this collection, was the son of Henry Clement Haight (1859-1936) and Emma Jane Young (1858-1939) and grandson of Alexander and Phebe Haight of the Civil War period.
Scope and Content
This collection contains materials of the Haight family, who have lived in Northern Virginia since the 1840s, and who owned Sully Plantation during the Civil War. Materials include correspondence, household financial records, photographs, Civil War documents, and artifacts. The artifacts in the collection consist of American Indian arrowheads and Civil War relics. Most of the materials date from the mid to late 19th century and the early 20th century, but the collection also includes a ledger dating from before the American Revolution and a few items dating from after the First World War.
Series 1, Correspondence, contains letters to and from members of the Haight family and their friends. Haight family members represented in this series include George, Helen, Henry, Margaret, and Phebe. Some of the letters refer to the California Gold Rush in which Alexander Haight's brother-in-law, George Sweet (1821-1898), participated as a "49er". Other letters refer to the Civil War in which Henry C. Haight's father-in-law, John M. Young (1831-1864), fought under the Union Army.
Series 2, Legal and Financial Documents, contains personal legal and financial records of the Haight family, including deeds, receipts, contracts, and documents from the Fairfax County Court House. Specific items include court orders from 1852-1853 appointing Alexander Haight as "surveyor of the county road"; an 1864 letter from Virginia District Judge John C. Underwood on a forthcoming war-time property-confiscation trial of Alexander Haight; bank receipts of Elizabeth Haight from 1914-1919; deeds of gift from George Haight, 1895-1903; correspondence from March of 1884 regarding damage claims by Phebe Haight from the West and Sisson railroad company for damaged packages of butter; and a financial accounting record of farm land sold to Samuel Titus and Nehemiah Sweet, dated January 16, 1843.
Series 3, Photographs, contains around twenty original photographs and reproductions belonging to the Haight family. Subjects include Alexander, Phebe, Elizabeth, George, and Helen Haight; Fairfax County Court House; Sully Plantation; Fairfax Station during the Civil War; Alexander Haight's prize horse; and Clio, a slave girl whom Phebe Haight kept at the Sully Plantation until 1862.
Series 4, Civil War Documents, contains various materials pertaining to the Civil War such as civilian passes, diary excerpts, and Confederate currency. Specific items include Civil War maps and photographs; an official order from General Jackson on the day of the Battle of Chantilly (Ox Hill) prohibiting the theft or destruction of private property; documents granting passage of Alexander Haight and company into and out of Virginia; a hand-written note from the Union Major General Julius Stahel to the Union Army, attesting to the good standing of Alexander Haight; receipts of Alexander Haight for Union and Confederate supplies given out during the war; and a typed manuscript detailing the Civil War experiences of the Sutton family in Fairfax, excerpted from the diaries of Charles and Phebe Sutton.
Series 5, Publications and Serials, contains seven illustrated monthly magazines and a book titled War Reminiscences by the Surgeon of Mosby's Command (1890). The magazines include issues of The Century, The Cosmopolitan, and McClure's.
Series 6, Miscellaneous, contains miscellaneous printed materials, notes, and facsimiles. Materials include old business cards; brochures on local history; a newspaper facsimile (circa 1975) on old Fairfax families, the Haights and Milans; a scrap book of old newsclippings; and a ledger full of accounting records dating from before the Revolutionary War.
Series 7, Oversize, includes Confederate bonds; a centennial print of the Declaration of Independence; and newspapers chronicling the sinking of the Titanic, the election of Franklin Roosevelt, and other historical events.
Series 8, Objects, contains Civil War Artifacts as well as ancient American Indian arrowheads and tools. The Civil War artifacts include three muskets, ammunition, a sword with scabbard, two bayonets, a cavalry bridle, and a hand-made crutch.
Arrangement
Organized into eight series by subject with each series organized alphabetically by title.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1838-1901; 1918-1920; 1974 (Box 1)
Series 2: Legal and Financial Documents, 1813; 1843-1918 (Box 2)
Series 3: Photographs, circa 1863-1920 (Box 3)
Series 4: Civil War Documents and Currency, 1861-1865 (Box 4)
Series 5: Printed Material, 1884-1900 (Box 5)
Series 6: Miscellaneous Documents, 1764-1976 (Boxes 6-8)
Series 7: Oversize, 1863-1966 (Box 9)
Series 8: Objects, 1860s (Boxes 10-19 and Unboxed Objects)
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives holds other collections pertaining to local history and the Civil War, including the.
Index Terms
Geographical Names:
United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Virginia, Northern--History, Local.
Document Types:
Daguerreotypes.; Negatives.; Photographic prints.; Reproductions.; Tintypes.
Contents List
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1838-1901; 1918-1920; 1974; (1 box)
  This series contains letters to and from members of the Haight family and their friends. Haight family members represented in this series include George, Helen, Henry, Margaret, and Phebe. Some of the letters refer to the California Gold Rush as Alexander Haight's brother-in-law, George Sweet (1821-1898), was a "49er". Other letters refer to the Civil War, in which Henry C. Haight's father-in-law, John M. Young (1831-1864), fought under the Union Army.
  - Haight family: Miscellaneous letters, 1838-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - E. R. Haight to Elisa, September 30, [1838]; 1.
    - To Dr. Layburn, 1838; 2.
      sender unknown
    - Laura to Maggie [Margaret Amy Haight], January 17, 1859; 3.
    - Elias Titus to Sister Margaret, September 13, 1871; 4.
    - [Phebe Haight] to P. Mason and Co., December 15, 1881; 5.
      from Syndhurst, New Jersey
    - To Mister Hate [Haight], December 28, 1885; 6.
    - Dear Sir, May 14, 1888; 7.
      sender and recipient unknown
    - Dear Sir, August 15, 1888; 8.
    - J. H. Haight to Cousin, December 17, 1901; 9.
    - Rusty to Uncle Alex [Alexander Levi Haight], August 23, 1974; 10.
    - D. A. Upson to Sir, undated; 11.
      recipient unknown
    - Partial letter to Jacob [Haight], undated (before 1863); 12.
    - C. J. and Sisters and Brothers, undated; 13.
    - Partial letter from S. B. Tus[ker], undated; 14.
      recipient unknown, but sender wrote "lots of love to yourself and boys, also to Maggie [Margaret Haight]"
    - Janie to unknown, undated; 15.
      postcard
  - Haight, George: Letters from friends and family, 1889-1910 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Henry Clement Haight to George Haight, January 5, 1889; 1.
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, January 8, 1889; 2.
    - Ida Jane Ginnelley to George Haight, April 29, 1889; 3.
    - Charles R. Murray to George Haight, April 30, 1889; 4.
    - Everett B. Whaley to George Haight, May 2, 1889; 5.
    - Henry [Haight] to George Haight, May 4, 1889; 6.
      includes envelope
    - Henry C. Haight to George Haight, June 8, 1889; 7.
    - Ida J. Ginnelley to George Haight, June 16, 1889; 8.
    - Aunt Maria to George Haight, July 24, 1889; 9.
    - Maria to George Haight, December 30, 1889; 10.
    - Henry C. Haight to George Haight, January 28, 1890; 11.
    - N. and W.R.R. Machine Shop to George Haight, April 29, 1891; 12.
    - Thomas P. Morgan of the Mutual Life Insurance Company to George Haight, November 3, 1910; 13.
    - Sister [Margaret Haight] to Brother [George Haight], undated; 14.
      includes envelope, "missent"
  - Haight, George: Letters from Mother [Phebe Haight], 1888-1890 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, October 1, 1888; 1.
      includes envelope postmarked October 4, 1888
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, [November 21, 1888]; 2.
      includes envelope postmarked November 21, 1888
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, December 31, [1888]; 3.
      includes envelope postmarked January 1, 1889
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, February 20, 1889; 4.
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, March 10, 1889; 5.
      includes envelope postmarked March 12, 1889
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, March 28, 1889; 6.
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, March 31, 1889; 7.
      partial letter; includes envelope postmarked April 2, 1889
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, April 5, 1889; 8.
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, April 18, 1889; 9.
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, April 23, [1889]; 10.
      includes envelope postmarked April 30, 1889
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, November 14, 1889; 11.
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, January 13, 1890; 12.
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, May 12, [1890]; 13.
      includes envelope postmarked May 13, 1890
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, January, [no year]; 14.
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, February 28, [no year]; 15.
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, September 17, [no year]; 16.
      includes envelope postmarked September 19
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, December 31, [no year]; 17.
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, undated; 18.
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, undated; 19.
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, undated; 20.
    - Mother [Phebe Haight] to George Haight, undated; 21.
    - Seven envelopes addressed to George Haight, postmarked February 23, 1889; April 19-20, 1889; April 30-May 1, 1889; October 7-8, 1889; January 29-30, 1890; April 10-11, 1890; 22.
  - Haight, Helen: Letters to and from family, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Helen Haight to Alexander Haight, November 5, 1918; 1.
    - Helen Haight to Mamma [Emma Jane Haight], November 5, 1918; 2.
    - Helen Haight to Mamma [Emma Jane Haight], November 16, 1918; 3.
    - Helen Haight to Mamma [Emma Jane Haight], November 18, 1918; 4.
    - Helen Haight to Mamma [Emma Jane Haight], November 19, 1918; 5.
    - Helen Haight to Mamma [Emma Jane Haight], November 19, 1918; 6.
    - Emma Jane Haight to Helen Haight, December 15, 1918; 7.
    - Emma Jane Haight to Helen Haight, November 18, 1918; 8.
    - Alexander to Helen Haight, December 1, 1918; 9.
    - Mother [Emma Jane Haight] to Helen Haight, December 2, 1918; 10.
    - Mother [Emma Jane Haight] to Helen Haight, December 15, 1918; 11.
    - Mother [Emma Jane Haight] to Helen Haight, December 31, 1918; 12.
    - Mother [Emma Jane Haight] to Helen Haight, January 5, 1919; 13.
    - Mother [Emma Jane Haight] to Helen Haight, January 6, 1919; 14.
    - Alexander and Mother [Emma Jane Haight] to Helen, January 19, 1919; 15.
    - Mother [Emma Jane Haight] to Helen Haight, April 6, 1919; 16.
    - Mother [Emma Jane Haight] to Helen Haight, April 20, 1919; 17.
    - Alexander and Mother [Emma Jane Haight] to Helen Haight, April 27, 1919; 18.
    - Alexander to Helen Haight, May 11, 1919; 19.
    - Mother [Emma Jane Haight] to Helen Haight, May 18, 1919; 20.
    - Mother [Emma Jane Haight] to Helen Haight, undated; 21.
    - Aunt Ida [Mrs. Asa Conklin] to Helen Haight, April 13, 1919; 22.
    - Aunt Mary to Helen Haight, April 15, 1919; 23.
    - Aunt Stell to Helen Haight, April 18, [ca. 1919]; 24.
    - Bess [Helen's sister] to Helen Haight, May 15, 1919; 25.
    - Bess to Helen Haight, undated; 26.
    - Bess to Helen Haight, undated; 27.
    - Cousin Howard to Helen Haight, June 2, 1919; 28.
  - Haight, Helen: Letters from friends, pt. 1, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Louis Appezzito to Helen Haight, August 4, 1918; 1.
    - Louis Appezzito to Helen Haight, [August 9, 1918]; 2.
    - Louis Appezzito to Helen Haight, August 19, 1918; 3.
    - Louis Appezzito to Helen Haight, August 24, 1918; 4.
    - Louis Appezzito to Helen Haight, August 28, 1918; 5.
    - Louis Appezzito to Helen Haight, September 9, 1918; 6.
    - Louis Appezzito to Helen Haight, September 16, 1918; 7.
    - Louis Appezzito to Helen Haight, October 9, 1918; 8.
    - Louis Appezzito to Helen Haight, October 16, 1918; 9.
    - Louis Appezzito to Helen Haight, October 22, 1918; 10.
    - Louis Appezzito to Helen Haight, October 27, 1918; 11.
    - Louis Appezzito to Helen Haight, 1918; 12.
    - Louis Appezzito to Helen Haight, 1918; 13.
    - Domencio Lo Bianco to Helen Haight, July 31, 1918; 14.
    - Domencio Lo Bianco to Helen Haight, July 31, 1918; 15.
    - Domencio Lo Bianco to Helen Haight, August 2, 1918; 16.
    - Domencio Lo Bianco to Helen Haight, August 9, 1918; 17.
    - Domencio Lo Bianco to Helen Haight, October 5, 1918; 18.
    - Joseph Patton to Helen Haight, June 27, 1918; 19.
    - Joseph Patton to Helen Haight, July 4, 1918; 20.
    - Joseph Patton to Helen Haight, July 9, 1918; 21.
    - Joseph Patton to Helen Haight, July 14, 1918; 22.
    - Joseph Patton to Helen Haight, July 19, 1918; 23.
    - Joseph Patton to Helen Haight, July 27, 1918; 24.
    - Joseph Patton to Helen Haight, August 12, 1918; 25.
  - Haight, Helen: Letters from friends, pt. 2, 1918-1920 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Warren Parsons to Helen Haight, May 10, 1919; 1.
    - Warren Parsons to Helen Haight, May 12, 1919; 2.
      newsclipping
    - M. Earnest Taylor to Helen Haight, April 2, 1919; 3.
    - M. Earnest Taylor to Helen Haight, May 8, 1919; 4.
    - M. Earnest Taylor to Helen Haight, June 16, 1919; 5.
    - Jack Thompson to Helen Haight, March 23, 1919; 6.
    - Jack Thompson to Helen Haight, March 25, [1919]; 7.
    - Jack Thompson to Helen Haight, April 4, 1919; 8.
    - Jack Thompson to Helen Haight, April 12, 1919; 9.
    - Jack Thompson to Helen Haight, April 29, 1919, 1918; 10.
    - Jack Thompson to Helen Haight, May 16, 1919; 11.
    - Elsie [Mrs. W. A. Hart] to Helen Haight, May 14, 1919; 12.
    - Mrs. L. Lee to Helen Haight, April 15, 1919; 13.
      envelope only
    - Corporal Murice J. Marrits to Helen Haight, March 28, 1919; 14.
    - Mollie V. Walker to Helen Haight, May 4, 1919; 15.
    - G. L. Welton to Helen Haight, April 14, 1919; 16.
    - G. L. Welton to Helen Haight, May 7, 1919; 17.
    - G. L. Welton to Helen Haight, May 20, 1919; 18.
    - G. L. Welton to Helen Haight, February 29, 1920; 19.
      newsclippings
    - Raban to Helen Haight, January 1, 1919; 20.
    - Pvt. 1st Cl. Harry W. Schubele to Helen Haight, March 16, 1919; 21.
    - Mary C. Curly to Helen Haight, April 22, 1919; 22.
      Easter postcard
    - Nellie Leyburn to Helen Haight, April 22, 1919; 23.
    - Private Charles C. Goodman to Helen Haight, May 20, 1919; 24.
    - Mac to Helen Haight, January 29, 1920; 25.
    - Houser Harbour to Helen Haight, February 15, 1920; 26.
    - Mildred Haveus to Helen Haight, February 26, 1920; 27.
  - Haight, Phebe: Letters from son, Henry Clement Haight, 1883-1886 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Henry C. Haight to Mother [Phebe Haight], November 27, 1883; 1.
    - Henry C. Haight to Mother [Phebe Haight], November 30, 1883; 2.
    - Henry C. Haight to Mother [Phebe Haight], December 4, 1883; 3.
    - Henry C. Haight to Mother [Phebe Haight], December 13, 1883; 4.
    - Henry C. Haight to Mother [Phebe Haight], December 15, 1883; 5.
    - Henry C. Haight to Mother [Phebe Haight], December 26, 1883; 6.
    - Henry C. Haight to Mother [Phebe Haight], December 31, 1883; 7.
    - Henry C. Haight to Mother [Phebe Haight], January 7, 1884; 8.
    - Henry C. Haight to Mother [Phebe Haight], January 19, 1884; 9.
    - Henry C. Haight to Mother [Phebe Haight], January 23, 1884; 10.
    - Henry C. Haight to Mother [Phebe Haight], January 29, 1884; 11.
    - Henry C. Haight to Mother [Phebe Haight], February 1, 1884; 12.
    - Henry C. Haight to Mother [Phebe Haight], February 9, 1884; 13.
    - Henry C. Haight to Mother [Phebe Haight], February 13, 1884; 14.
    - Henry C. Haight to Mother [Phebe Haight], February 18, 1884; 15.
    - Henry C. Haight to Mother [Phebe Haight], February 29, 1884; 16.
    - Henry C. Haight to Mother [Phebe Haight], July 4, 1886; 17.
  - Haight, Phebe: Letters from family, 1849-1898 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Phebe Ham to Cousin, May 26, 1849; 1.
      contains reference to the California Gold Rush
    - Elizabeth to Sister [Phebe Haight], March 10, 1850; 2.
    - E. T. Frances to Cousin [Phebe Haight], November 20, 1851; 3.
    - Cousin Molly T. to Phebe [Haight], April 5, 1855; 4.
    - Alfred H. [Titus] to Cousin [Phebe Haight], April 10, 186[5]; 5.
      near Blakely Alabama; reference to Union Army
    - Elizabeth to Sister [Phebe Haight], March 2, [1886]; 6.
      contains reference to Andrew Johnson's impeachment
    - Mother [Margaret Titus] to Phebe Haight [daughter], January 11, 1869; 7.
    - George Sweet to Sister [Phebe Haight], November 20, 1877; 8.
    - Mary T. Haight to Phebe [Haight], July 23, 1884; 9.
    - Emma [Jane Haight] to Phebe Haight [mother-in-law], July 10, 1886; 10.
    - John W. Ham to Cousin [Phebe Haight], May 11, 1898; 11.
    - John W. Ham to Cousin [Phebe Haight], June 16, 1898; 12.
    - Elizabeth to Sister [Phebe Haight], August 14, [no year]; 13.
    - Mary T. Haight to Phebe [Haight], April 22, [no year]; 14.
  - Haight, Phebe: Letters from friends, 1883-1884 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Cecilia Searle to Mrs. [Phebe] Haight, December 24, 1883; 1.
    - Sue R. Horley to Phebe Haight, March 2, 1884; 2.
      includes envelope from Philadelphia postmarked March 4, 1884
    - J. T. and J. G. Beckham to Phebe Haight, March 14, 1884; 3.
      includes envelope from Alexandria, Virginia postmarked March 14
    - Unknown sender to Mrs. Phebe Haight, June 13, 1886; 4.
      includes envelope from Canon City, Colorado postmarked June 25, 1886
    - Cecilia Searle to Mrs. [Phebe] Haight and Boys, November 2, 1886; 5.
    - Everett Whaley to Friend [Phebe Haight], October 10, 1888; 6.
    - Sarah to Phebe Haight, December 28, [no year]; 7.
    - David S. Johnson to Phebe Haight, undated; 8.
    - Three envelopes to Phebe Haight, postmarked December 29, 1884; February 19th; March 4th; 9.
  - Harnesberger, Reverend Alfred L., 1893-1919 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - To A. L. Harnesberger, March 23, 1893; 1.
      sender's signature illegible; includes envelope
    - PAB to Nell, April 19th, 1915; 2.
      postcard addressed to A. L. Harnesberger
    - V. B. Bishop to Harnesberger, November 16 and November 23, 1915; 3.
      2 typewritten letters; includes 1 envelope
    - Pat to Alfred [Harnesberger], February 17, 1919; 4.
    - Envelope addressed to Harnesberger, October 20, 1893; 5.
  - Miller, P. S. of Miller and Co. Wagons to W. M. Firebaugh, October 18, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    includes envelope postmarked November 9, 1893
  - Sweet, George: Letters, 1849-1894 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - George Sweet to Sister, December 20, 1849; 1.
      George Sweet had two sisters, Phebe, who married Alexander Haight in 1824, and Elizabeth.
    - Cornelius Cornelle [to George Sweet], February 21, 1851; 2.
      on interest "received of George Sweet" from gold dug in the California Gold Rush.
    - Horace Greeley to George Sweet, May 7, 1858; 3.
      Greeley's signature matches that of the renowned journalist and founder of the New York Tribune.
    - Benson J. Lossing to George Sweet, June 8, 1876; 4.
    - Benson J. Lossing to George Sweet, June 5, 1877; 5.
    - J. H. Ketcharn to Friend [George] Sweet, October 10, 1888; 6.
    - Benny D. Hicks to George Sweet, June 23, 1894; 7.
    - George Sweet to Phebe Sweet: Hand-written transcription, 1849 (year of original letter); 8.
      partial letter; contains references to the California Gold Rush
    - Envelope addressed to George Sweet, undated; 9.
  - Young, John M: Civil War correspondence to wife, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - John M. Young to Wife, Rosetta R. Young, August 2, 1862; 1.
      The letters in this folder contain references to John Young's service with the Union Army during the Civil War.
    - John M. Young to Wife, Rosetta R. Young, December 5, 1862; 2.
    - John M. Young to Wife, Rosetta R. Young, and Children, December 10, 1862; 3.
    - John M. Young to Wife, Rosetta R. Young, December 19, 1862; 4.
      at camp near Fredericksburg, Virginia; includes envelope and transcription
    - John M. Young to Wife, Rosetta R. Young, and Children, May 12, [ca. 1862-1863]; 5.
  - Young, John M.: Transcriptions of letters to wife, 1862-1863 (indicates dates of original letters) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    This folder contains 37 pages of transcriptions of letters written from John M. Young to his wife, Rosetta, during his service with the Union Army.
- Series 2: Legal and Financial Documents, 1813; 1852-1918; (1 box)